Oghenefejiro Abohweyere

Software Engineer

289-943-0202 | theodore.abohweyere@gmail.com | Ontario, Canada | GitHub | LinkedIn | Website

SUMMARY

Versatile software engineer with 5+ years of experience developing, testing and maintaining software.

Secured \$100K+ of government funding while working on an app with bulk download and peer-to-peer networking features. Improved the scalability of the backend services for a behavioural therapy app with 75K monthly active users.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, 247 Labs Inc., Toronto, Canada

Apr 2022 - Present

- Secured \$100K+ in government funding by using Java, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, AWS SQS and S3 to develop a bulk download distributed system in a backend API, increasing mean download speed by 15%.
- Engineered JavaScript database adapters to allow migration to AWS DynamoDB from MongoDB, reducing scaling costs by 9% for the Node.js REST API powering a behavioural therapy app with 75K monthly active users.
- Developed a multi-modal AI chatbot using Next.js React, Tailwind CSS, Python, PostgreSQL, S3 and LLM APIs from AWS Bedrock, improving user engagement by 18%.
- Built a TURN/STUN server Docker container that accepts environment variables to make it easier for other developers to deploy configurable critical peer-to-peer network infrastructure and improve productivity.
- Implemented CI/CD automation pipelines using tools like GitHub Actions, Docker, Go and Terraform CDK while deploying backend applications to cloud platforms like Azure and AWS.

Software Engineer, Upwork Inc., San Francisco, United States

Jul 2019 - Mar 2022

- Developed an admin dashboard using Next.js React, Tailwind CSS and a Python REST API, enabling monitoring of system metrics, reducing administrative task completion times significantly.
- Optimized SQL queries for relational databases (PostgreSQL, MySQL), significantly improving query performance.
- Optimized backend API performance through caching using Redis, achieving a 40% reduction in response times for high traffic endpoints.
- Reduced image sizes by 20% using Docker multi-stage builds, to increase efficiency while deploying backend APIs.
- Collaborated using GitHub workflows, creating pull requests, conducting code reviews, and soliciting feedback from peers to deliver high-quality, maintainable code.

EDUCATION

Ontario Tech University, Oshawa, Canada - Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Jan 2019 - May 2023

PROJECTS

3-way merge Go API, Link

- Designed a Go REST backend API that automatically merges changes in 3 versions of a file into a single merged file using a 3-way merge algorithm, replicating the Git merge feature.
- Created a UI tool using Next.js React and Tailwind CSS to allow users interact with the 3-way merge backend, enhancing accessibility for data manipulation while providing clear conflict resolution paths for versioned data.
- Automated deployment of backend API using AWS Lambda and AWS CDK, significantly improving deployment speed.

BTree Database Index, Link

- Implemented a BTree data structure using C++ as the backbone of a larger custom database project.
- Developed unit tests for the data structure, ensuring robustness through automated testing and build validation using CMake and Catch2 test framework, demonstrating attention to reliable, fault-tolerant system design.

NTP, Link

- Built a C++ client that uses the Network Time Protocol (NTP) to retrieve accurate UTC time from sources like GPS satellites for clock synchronization in networked systems.
- Engineered C++ helper functions using bit manipulation to parse and assemble data efficiently, enhancing performance and efficiency.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Go, Python, TypeScript, JavaScript, C#, C++ **Front End**: React, Vue, Tailwind, CSS, HTML, JQuery, Figma

Database : SQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, AWS DynamoDB, MongoDB, DocumentDB

Project Management: Jira, Confluence

Cloud Services : AWS (SQS, Lambda, S3, RDS, Elastic Beanstalk, EKS), Docker, Terraform, Azure

Testing : JUnit, Pytest, NUnit, Selenium